ABHISHEK SHESHAGIRI

linkedin/abhishekds94 github/abhishekds94 www.abhishekds.site Email: abhishekds94@gmail.com

Mobile: +1(217)761-5585 Springfield, IL, USA. 62704

Summary

A self-directed and motivated Mobile Developer with a passion for creating beautiful UI, experimenting with patterns of the user experience through a mobile device to solve a real-time problem. Experienced in design and development with modern Android stacks like MVVM architecture, Live Data, REST APIs and Material Design

Work Experience

Information Technology Services

University of Illinois, Springfield

August 2019 - Present

- Graduate Student Assistant with Tuition Scholarship
 - o Mobile Development: Developing hybrid mobile apps in Flutter to make the campus go digital
 - o Web Development: Developing web applications for the campus in Laravel PHP using Vue and Quasar frameworks

Radiant IT World

Shimoga, Karnataka, India

February 2018 - November 2018

- Mobile Applications developer Best Employee, 2018
 - Worked on an image-based social-networking application where reduced the image fetch and upload time by nearly 60 percent by using Volley instead of Retrofit and Glide libraries
 - Fixed a security breakout in less than 6 hours by releasing a patch that was optimized to check the image header before the media upload to prevent any injections and attacks to the server
 - Developed two Hybrid mobile applications using React Native. Apps were developed for Android and iOS platforms with flex layouts and normal layouts and Worked on retrieving data from JSON response using REST APIs to parse it to UI modules. The apps were only 1.1 MB and 1.6 MB in size which increased its overall performance by 70 percent even on low latency (2G and 3G) networks

Pyplyn

Bangalore, India

Android Developer - Full Stack

July 2017 - January 2018

- Developed an Educational Android application using Java, PHP, MySQL, and Firebase with built-in Video players to stream the video tutorials. The application had around 800-900 daily users
- Worked on a Bank application in which the security features such as Fingerprint and OTP based login were implemented which increased
 the security of the application by 80 percent and used SQLite to store non-vital information which increased the application performance
 by 30 percent

Anugraha Computers

Shimoga, Karnataka, India

Android Developer

August 2016 - April 2017

- City Center: Developed a parking ticket application for a popular shopping complex group. The application gave the slots to the
 customers as to where they could park their vehicles when they enter the parking area of the shopping complex. This was developed
 using Firebase as the service provider. The application was used in 35 shopping malls across the State and was generating around
 300,000 tickets everyday
- Yatra Cabs: Integrated an emergency services option in a popular taxi (ride-sharing) service application. The integration was about displaying the nearest hospital from the current location with Navigation and also an automated text message to the police control room about the start and the endpoints of the route. The integration was developed using Geo-fencing technology with volley services to send and receive requests and also Google Maps SDK to populate the navigation to the nearest Hospital
- Loki Mo-bikes: Developed an Admin application for a two-wheeler booking company. The app had various features to check the
 bookings that were done by the users based on different locations and dates. The application used a REST API to retrieve the response
 from the database that was provided by the client
- Truth or Dare: Developed a Truth or Dare game using Firebase as back-end. The application allows players to play the truth or dare game for a maximum of 5 players at any given time

EDUCATION

Master of Science, Computer Science

Springfield, IL

University of Illinois at Springfield

Bachelor of Engineering, Computer Science

May 2020 Shimoga, Karnataka, India July 2017

Jawaharlal Nehru National College of Engineering
Android Developer Nanodegree Program

Udacity.com

Online certification for Android developers with experience in developing mobile applications in Java

May 2020

SKILLS

Java, Kotlin, Flutter, PHP, MySQL, Javascript, AWS, Espresso, Crashlytics, ROOM, Algorithms, Data Structures, Object Oriented Programming, Android Design Concepts

Bakers Bowl, An Android Application: (February 2020 - March 2020)

- An application for users to display various recipes with step-wise instructions using video tutorials
- Used REST API, Fragments and Exo-Player to develop this application
- Added a home screen widget function with an automated Espresso testing functionality to increase the effective performance of the application

UIS Walking Routes, A Flutter based Hybrid Mobile Application: (November 2019 - December 2019)

- An application for users to check the Distance traveled, Calories burnt, and Time spent on walking routes in campus with live tracking
- Used Google Maps SDK, OpenWeather API and Email Client library for email feedback without server

Motor Insurance Premium Calculator, An Android Application: (January 2018 - March 2018)

- An application developed using basic java concepts for calculating Motor Insurance Premium, it is now used across India by various Insurance companies
- The app has more than 50,000 downloads to-date

Smart Parent, A React Native Hybrid Mobile Application: (March 2017 - April 2017)

- An application that serves as a digital dashboard for Parents and the Teachers with a one-one chat window in all schools
- The application was built using PHP-MySQL as backend server to store the data along with Firebase for chat, notifications and authentication

Locatify, An Android Application: (February 2016)

- This application was developed for the Government of India under Make in India program to provide a manual green corridor for all the emergency vehicles in metropolitan cities
- The Application was developed using Geo-fencing technology with Google Maps SDK, Firebase Realtime database and Notifications with a provision to connect to any IoT devices to control the traffic signals
- This application was judged as the Most Popular Project in the hackathon by the Government of India